本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 修正调整
欢迎爱好者加入我们 www.YYeTs.com
■
双语字幕:七色九天      后期:奥秘
秋天
一切都是从这沙发开始
It started with a chair.
我等这刻已久了
I've wanted this for a really long time.
我知道
I know.
等等
Wizard.
老天!  巴拿拉  闭上你的狗嘴好吗?
Jeez Banana, shut your freakin' gob OK?
眼前的是我看过最豪华的天然客厅
This is the most magnificent discarded living room set I've ever seen.
哇  你还挺悠然的嘛?
Well, well, if it isn't MacGuff the Crime Dog.
又要测吗?
Back for another test?
我认为第一次测试效果不好
I think the first one was defective,
阳性指示不清晰  我还是不太相信
The plus sign looks more like a division symbol, so I remain unconvinced.
你已经测三次了 "准妈妈" 就是怀孕  别怀疑
Third test today, Momma Bear, your eggo's preggo, no doubt about it.
想知道很容易  你乳头有变深色吗?
It's really easy to tell, is your nipples real brown?
或许你男友的"种子" 已经在你肚里生两次根了
Yeah, maybe your little boyfriend's got mutant sperms, knocked you up twice.
闭嘴老头!  我一路来喝了两升橙汁  我快要狂喷尿出来了
Silencio, old man. Look, I just drank my weight in SunnyD and I gotta go pronto.
你知道去那里上小号
Well, you know where the lavatory is.
回来再付钱
Pay for that pee stick when you're done.
别以为它沾上了你的尿液  就变成你的了
Don't think it's yours just 'cause you marked it with your urine.
你该不会大吃一惊吧  都是事实了
What's the prognosis, Fertile Myrtle: Minus or plus?
谁知道  现在还未显示
I don't know, it's not seasoned yet.
我还要这个
I'll take some of these.
现在  有结果了
There it is.
粉红色的正号标记  真是无法相信
The little pink plus sign is so unholy.
我不明白你费什么劲  反正都是无法改变的
That ain't no Etch- a- Sketch, this is one doodle that can't be undid, homeskillet.
我想要自杀了
I'm a suicide risk.
是朱诺吗?
Juno?
不  我是摩根・弗里曼  你有藏起人骨吗?(指电影情节)
No, it's Morgan Freeman, do you have any bones that need collecting?
我裤兜有根  你怎么了?
Only the one in my pants.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
什么?  你说真的?
What? Honest to blog?
对  是里克的种
Yeah, it's Bleeker's.
或许是食物宝宝  你中饭有吃很多吗?
It's probably just a food baby, did you have a big lunch?
不是食物宝宝  我做了三次测试  十分肯定
This is not a food baby, I've taken three pregnancy tests and I am fo' shiz up the spout.
你一天内怎做到三次的?  太不可置信了
How did you even generate enough pee for three pregnancy tests? That's amazing.
我不知道  反正我是喝了10吨的果汁
I don't know, I drank like ten tons of SunnyD.
我说我怀孕了  你却表现得毫不惊讶
I'm telling you I'm pregnant and you're acting shockingly cavalier.
真的?  是真实的真吗?
Is this for real? Like for real for real?
很不幸  是的
Unfortunately yes.
噢!  我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
噢!  该死!  去他的!
Oh shit! Phuket Thailand!
这才是我一开始就期待的反应
That was kind of the emotion that I was searching for on the first take.
你打算去"布克天堂"或"真女人"(堕胎机构)吗?
Are you going to Havenbrook or Women Now?
去"布克天堂"要父母签字才可以
You need a note from your parents for Havenbrook.
我打算去"真女人"  因为他们帮的都是真女人
Yeah, I know. No, I'm going to go to Women Now, just 'cause they help out women now.
要我帮你预约吗?  我去年就帮过碧奇
Do you want me to call for you? Because I called for Becky last year.
不用了  我自己可以
No, I can call myself.
不过有件更重要的事情需要你帮忙
Oh, but I do need your help with something, it's like critically important.
知道吗  这份上我倒是  帮忙干重活的好帮手
You know, heavy lifting can really only help you at this point.
真的假的?
Seriously.
你是无聊才想要的(怀孕)吗?
So, you were bored? That's how this blessed miracle came to be?
我们计划好的  我是说做爱  怀孕不在计划内
No, the act was premeditated. I mean, the sex, not the whole "let's get pregnant" thing.
你什么时候决定搭上里克的?
So, when did you decide that you were gonna do Bleeker?
不清楚
I don't know.
一年前的西班牙语课上
A year ago in Spanish class.
你喜欢他
You love him.
不是这样  其实蛮复杂
It's actually really complicated, OK?
而我不太想在现在情况下说
And I don't feel like talking about it in my fragile state.
和他干感觉如何?
So what was it like?
像抱着根树干?
Humping Bleek's bony bod?
激昂澎湃吧
Magnificent.
好吗  里克
Hey, Bleek.
好猛的老虎
Wicked tiger.
衬起你很有贵气
It looks proud.
我从莎伦阿姨那顺手牵羊来的
I swiped it from Ms. Rancick's lawn.
为何  你的衬衫今天特别金黄
Wow, your shorts are like especially gold today.
我老妈说亮颜色能让人精神点
My mom uses color- safe bleach.
跟她说很好
Go Carole.
我会跟她说
I'll tell her.
每当我看到他们一路跑  一路摇着自己的"东西"
When I see them all running like that, with their things bouncing around in their shorts,
我总幻想他们裸体的样子  尽管我不太喜欢看到那"东西"
I always picture them naked, even if I don't want to, all I see is pork swords.
我想我该一起跑了
I'm supposed to be running.
给你猜点东西
So guess what.
什么?  我不知道
What? I don't know.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我们要怎么做?
What should we do?
你明白  我只想在事情闹大前快点了事
Oh, you know, I was thinking I'd just nip it in the bud before it gets worse.
因为课堂上也有学过怀孕是什么
Because they were talking about it in health class,
还有会导致个婴儿出世
how pregnancy can often lead to an infant.
对  很对
Typically, yeah, yeah.
就好象我们妈妈  老师怀孕时候一样
That's what happens when our moms and teachers get pregnant.
你接受得了吗?
So, you're cool with that then?
是的  当然  你知道
Yeah, yeah, wizard. You know,
我想你就按自己想法去做吧
do whatever you think you should do, you know?
哦  抱歉把你搞上床了
Well, I'm sorry I had sex with you,
那不是你想的
I know it wasn't your idea.
什么  是谁想的?
Whose idea was it?
我们学校再见  好吧?!
I'll see you at school, alright?
那是谁的主意?
Whose idea was it?
你的书都烂成一堆了
Hey, your book fell apart.
为什么会这样?
Right.
物似主人形吧
It must have looked at your face.
有趣的是史迪夫暗恋我
The funny thing is that Steve Rendazo secretly wants me.
因为他们喜欢那些不入流的女孩子
Jocks like him always want freaky girls.
那些戴黑框眼镜  穿老土裤子和奇怪装扮的女孩
Girls with horn- rimmed glasses and vegan footwear and Goth makeup.
然后会拉大提琴  看无聊杂志
Girls who play the cello and read McSweeney's and
长大后成为图书管理员的女孩
want to be children's librarians when they grow up.
对的  他们就喜欢那路货色
Oh yeah, jocks totally eat that shit up.
尽管他们不肯承认
They just won't admit it, because they're
因为他们本应追求完美的拉拉队长
supposed to be into perfect cheerleaders you know,
就如莉亚  不经意就招老师们喜欢
Like Leah, who incidentally is into teachers.
我也是啊  我很喜欢伍迪・艾伦
Me too, I love Woody Allen!
好了  同学们!
Alright people.
今天我们做光磁学实验
We're doing chromatography lab today, so find
四个人为一组
your partners and break into groups of four.
看上去一点也不像是要做实验
Well, there's nothing like experimenting.
我昨晚做了预习的问题
I did the prep questions for this lab last night,
你可以抄我的答案
so you can just copy my answers if you want.
我不可以抄你答案
I couldn't copy your work.
你每周都抄我的啊
You copy my work every week.
那倒是真的  我是个没有贡献的组员是吗?
True, I'm kind of a deadbeat lab partner, aren't I?
当然不  不要介意  我肯定你为小组做出过贡献
No, no, I don't mind. I think you definitely bring something to the table.
某些方面
Charisma.
好了  大家都准备好做实验了?
Who's ready for some chromamagnificence?
我"大姨妈"来了头很痛  恐怕今天脑袋不太灵光
I have a menstrual migraine, so I can't really look at bright lights today.
我都叫你去医务室休息了  你就是不肯听
Amanda, I told you to go to the infirmary and lie down. You never listen.
才不呢  左治  我可不是个听人摆布的机器人
No, Josh, because I don't take orders. Not from you and not from any man.
自我去看望我哥后
You know, you've been acting like this ever since
你就一直这样子
I got back from visiting my brother in Mankato.
我都说了  什么事也没发生
I already told you, nothing happened.
我先放置好仪器
Well, I'm gonna set up the apparatus.
朱诺  你可以放这些进去吗?
Juno, do you want to plug in the Bunsen burner?
很乐意
It's my pleasure.
我这就去医务室
I'm going to the infirmary.
很好  你"大姨妈"走了再叫我
Good. Call me when you get off the rag.
那好  当你学会了怎么
Fine, call me when you learn how to love someone,
爱一个人再打给我
instead of cheating at your brother's college,
学你哥那样会撒谎
Just because you've had four Smirnoff Ices and
喝了一瓶冰桃味波本威士忌不认帐
a bottle of Snow Peak Peach flavored Boone's!
好的阿曼达  我一定会的  我会记下来的
Good, Amanda, I'll be sure to do that, I'll make a note of it.
我听说冰桃味是波本威士忌中最好的
I've actually heard that the Snow Peak Peach flavor is the best flavor of Boone's.
是吗?
Isn't that right, Bleek?
(怀孕了?  找真女人)
按你想要的服务
Oprimo numero dos.
你好  对  我想做人流手术
Yeah, I'm just calling to procure a hasty abortion.
什么?
What?
你可以等等吗  我弄弄我的(汉堡包)电话
Can you just hold on for a second, I'm on my hamburger phone.
好了  可以了
Okay, now I can,
对  已经深思熟虑了
Yeah, it's really awkward to talk on.
对的  我要做个人流
Yeah, I need an abortion.
16岁
Sixteen.
从发生关系后有2个月零4天了
I'm gonna say it's been about two months and four days since the sex,
或者有偏差 只是估计的
Mind you, that's just like a guestimation.
抱歉  我多久什么?
Sorry, how long have I been what?
噢  我很讨厌人们说"性生活"这词
Oh, I hate it when adults use the term "sexually active".
要怎么理解?
What does it even mean?
难道是某天要履行的  固定一种行为吗?!
Can I deactivate someday, or is this a permanent state of being?
我觉得那天晚上里克非常享受
I guess Bleeker went live that night we did it,
不是处男不会有那表情
I guess that's why he got that look on his face.
你真该去看看那个炉子
You should have seen this octopus furnace at work.
要穿上防护衣才能进去
I had to get out my Hazmat suit just to get into the thing.
我爸爸是退役军人  不过现在是H-vac的维修技工
My dad used to be in the Army, but now he's just your average HVAC specialist.
在我5岁时 他和我妈离了婚
He and my mom got divorced when I was five,
我妈和她新老公在阿拉桑娜州定居
She lives on a Havasu reservation in Arizona
还有三个代替我的孩子
with her new husband and three replacement kids.
还有她每年情人节都寄仙人掌给我
Oh, and she inexplicably mails me a cactus every Valentine's Day.
然后我会回谢她说
And I'm like, Thanks a heap, Coyote Ugly.
"比起这些仙人掌  被你抛弃的感受还不错"
This cactus- gram stings even worse than your abandonment.
这是我后妈布伦  她可是爱狗一族
That's my stepmom, Bren, she's completely obsessed with dogs.
她有间美容修甲沙龙  里面总有股药水味道
Owns a nail salon and always smells like methylmethacrylate.
朱诺 昨晚的搬运工作如何?
So Juno, how was your little maneuver last night?
你指什么?
Which maneuver, sir?
是指把客厅家具搬到另一处
The one where I moved an entire living room set from one lawn to the other,
还是指我干掉了64盎司的蓝色饮料
or the one where I downed a sixty- four ounce blue slushie in ten minutes?
朱诺  你对我的瓷缸做过什么吗?
Juno, did you by any chance barf in my urn?
麦克  你知道就是那个  我放在门廊里放水的缸
Mac, you know that nice urn by the front door, the one I got up in Stillwater?
早上我发现那里面
There was some blue shit,
有些很脏的蓝色呕吐物
I mean, gunk, stuff in there this morning.
我从没朝那里面呕吐过
I would never barf in your urn, Brenda.
我是说  或许是小玛丽吐的
I mean, maybe L.B. did it.
玛丽・比 如果你还把豆放上去
Liberty Bell, if you put one more Baco on that potato,
我就要狠狠打你个小屁股了
I'm gonna kick your little monkey butt.
每个小宝宝都想来这世界  每个小宝宝都想来这世界
All babies want to get borned! All babies want to get borned!
每个小宝宝都想来这世界
All babies want to get borned!
嘿  苏春
Hey Su- Chin.
你好  朱诺
Hi, Juno.
你好吗?
How are you?
不错  很好
You know, pretty solid.
你完成课堂布置的作业了?
So did you write that paper for Worth's class yet?
不  还没呢
No, not yet.
我昨晚想过做了  不过有点精神不集中
I tried to work on it a little last night, but I'm having trouble concentrating.
如果你需要可以吃点安非他明
I'll sell you some of my Adderall.
不了  谢谢  我不嗑药
No thanks, I'm off pills.
这个选择不错  你知道我认识个女孩
That's a wise choice 'cause I knew this girl, she had this crazy freakout.
她嗑了很多安非他明  然后脱光衣服
She took too many behavioral meds at once and she ripped off her clothes
跑进大商场  大叫着说 "我是大海来的女妖"
and dove into the fountain at Ridgedale Mall like, Blaaaaah! I'm a kraken from the sea!
那是你吗?
I heard that was you.
真高兴见到你  苏春
It was good seeing you, Su- Chin.
你的宝宝现在可能心跳加速  知道吗?
Your baby probably has a beating heart, you know?
它会感觉到痛了
It can feel pain,
还有  指甲了
And it has fingernails.
手指甲?  真的?
Fingernails? Really?
欢迎来"真女人"  我们是你值得信任的朋友
Welcome to Women Now, where women are trusted friends.
请把手抬起来  放到柜台前
Please put your hands where I can see them and surrender any bombs.
嘿  我是来表演大魔术的!
Hey, I'm here for the big show.
名字!
Your name, please?
朱诺・麦高夫
Juno MacGuff.
她认为我用的是个假名
She thinks I'm using a fake name.
比如"让・斯蒂沃德"或"德兰修女"
Like Gene Simmons or Mother Teresa.
我需要你把两面都填了
I need you to fill these out, both sides.
还有任何细节任何来源
We need to know about every score and every sore.
要免费的套吗?
Would you like a free condom?
是草莓味的
They're boysenberry.
不了 我现在对性冷淡
No, I'm off sex.
我男友每次和我做爱都用
My boyfriend uses them every time we have intercourse.
他下体闻起来就像块蛋糕派
They make his jocks smell like pie.
每个小宝宝都想来这世界  每个小宝宝都想来这世界
All babies want to get borned! All babies want to get borned!
上帝会感谢你的奇迹!
God appreciates your miracle!
伙计  你来这里干嘛呢?
Dude, what are you doing here?
我以为四点才去接你
I'm supposed to come get you at four.
我做不到
I couldn't do it, Leah!
那里总感觉有个牙科诊室
It smelled like a dentist office in there,
杂志沾满恶心的水渍
And there were these horrible magazines with water stains.
还有那个柜台小妞不断
And then the friggin' receptionist is trying to
推销像超级奶嘴般的免费安全套
give me these condoms that looked like grape suckers,
然后吹嘘自己男友的蛋蛋像块蛋糕派
and just babbling away about her friggin' boyfriend's pie balls.
不错
Yum!
苏春也在那
And Su- Chin was there, and she was
然后说"嗨  宝宝有指甲"
like, "Oh hi! Babies have fingernails. "
指甲啊!
Fingernails!
那可真怪异
That's gruesome.
你有想过宝宝会挖破肚皮出来?
You think the baby can scratch your vag on the way out?
莉亚  我在怀孕呢!
I'm staying pregnant, Leah.
姐妹  不要那么大声  我妈妈在里面
Dude! You gotta keep your voice down, my mom is inside.
她还不知道我们已经有性生活了
She doesn't know that we're sexually active.
那又说明什么了?
What does that even mean?
我有想过
I've been thinking.
让宝宝出生  然后送给需要它的人
I was thinking that I could have this baby and give it to someone who totally needs it.
比如无法生育的妇女  或者善良的女同性恋
You know, like a woman with a bum ovary or a couple of nice lesbos.
不过你会变得很胖  胸部渗出乳汁
But then you're gonna get huge and your chest is gonna milktate.
并且你必须告诉别人你怀孕了
And you have to tell people that you're pregnant.
或许人们会赞许我的无私
But maybe they'll canonize me for being so selfless.
或许给脸色你看且对你不善
Maybe they'll totally shit and be really mad and
不让你毕业  或不让你去卡波春游
not let you graduate or go to Cabo for spring break.
我和里克计划去其他地方
I was going to go to Gettysburg with Bleeker anyway.
你应该看看收养信息
You should look at adoption ads,
我在《Penny Saver》经常看到(免费邮购周刊)
I see them all the time in the Penny Saver.
有推销父母的广告?
They have ads for parents?
对
Yeah!
就好像推销其他货品的广告一样
Desperately Seeking Spawn.Right next to terriers and iguanas and used fitness equipment.
是完全合法的
It's totally legit.
家庭美满  彼此恩爱的夫妇
"Wholesome, spiritually wealthy couple have found true love with each other. "
就差自己的孩子
"All that's missing is your bastard. "
我想要只鹦鹉
I want a parakeet.
朱诺  你根本没在听我说
You're totally not even listening to me.
我不太想把宝宝送给
No, I heard you. I don't want to give the baby
那些自称美满的家庭
to a family that describes themselves as "wholesome. "
-为什么?  -我想要比较活跃点的父母
- Why? - I want something a little more edgier.
-那你理想类型是什么?  -平面造型设计师不错
- Okay, what did you have in mind exactly? - I was thinking a graphic designer,
30岁左右
mid- thirties,
老婆是亚裔人  穿着得体而且会弹吉他
with a cool Asian girlfriend who dresses awesome and rocks out on the bass guitar.
不过不要过于与众不同的
But I don't want to be too particular.
好  这对怎么样?
OK, how about this?
受过高等教育事业成功的年轻夫妇  加入他们的五人家庭
"Educated, successful couple seeking infant to join our family of five."
会有报酬  请帮助我们完成爱的轮回
"You will be compensated. Help us complete the circle of love. "
听起来不错
That sounds great.
比较像宗买卖  而且他们已有三个孩子
They sound like a friggin' cult. Besides, they already have three kids,
听起来他们是贪心的混蛋
they're greedy little bitches.
噢  朱诺  这对怎么样?
Oh, Juno! How about this one?
他们是马克和瓦内萨・罗琳
They were Mark and Vanessa Loring,
一张很漂亮的黑白照
And they were beautiful even in black and white.
嘿  孩子  要下楼吃东西吗?
Paul? Are you coming downstairs to eat?
我想不用了
No, I don't think so.
你今天跑了8公里  宝贝
You ran eight miles today, Puppy.
我肚子还未饿
I'm not hungry, oddly.
是早餐加晚餐  你最喜欢的搭配
But it's breakfast for supper. It's your favorite, Paul.
好
Yeah.
今天你去跑步的时候  朱诺・麦高夫电话你了
Juno MacGuff called while you were out running today.
你知道我对她的看法
You know how I feel about her.
是的  你跟我说过很多次
You've mentioned it a couple times.
她比较
She is just...
与众不同
...different.
对
Yeah.
我不知道从何说起
I'm not really sure how I'm gonna spit this out.
你是怎么被开除的?
Hon, did you get expelled?
不是  如果我被开除学校会先联系你们
No. The school would most likely contact you in the event of my expulsion.
我只是问问  看上去有这可能
Well, I was just asking. It seemed plausible.
你想要大笔钱吗?  还是律师?
Do you need a large amount of money? Legal counsel?
我不需要什么
No, I'm not asking for anything.
除了宽容  没人因此而揍我就最好
Except for maybe mercy. Like, it would be friggin' sweet if no one hit me.
你做了什么?  用车子撞人了?
What have you done, Junebug? Did you hit someone with the Previa?
不是
No.
姐妹  我认为还是直接说好点
Dude, I think it's best to just tell them.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
噢  上帝啊!
Oh, God.
我已经放弃堕胎了
But I'm going to give it up for adoption.
我找到了一对不错的夫妇
I already found the perfect couple.
他们会付医药和所有的费用
They're gonna pay for the medical expenses and everything.
然后30周后就可以当什么事也没发生过
In thirty- odd weeks we can just pretend that this never happened.
你有宝宝了?
You're pregnant?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但我这就是我得到的安慰
I'm sorry. And if it is any consolation,
我心口和膝盖都感到火辣辣的痛
I have heartburn that's radiating down to my kneecaps
我从周三开始就没拉过屎了
and I haven't take a dump since Wednesday.
从周三早上
Morning!
我们不知道你已经有性生活了
I didn't even know you were sexually active!
那孩子长什么样?
Who is the kid?
我还不太清楚  你知道  大概有指甲了
The baby? I don't really know much about it. It has fingernails, allegedly.
指甲?  真的?
Nails? Really?
对
Yeah.
我是说孩子的父亲是谁?  朱诺
I mean, who is the father, Juno?
是保利・里克
It's Paulie Bleeker.
保利・里克?
Paulie Bleeker?
怎么了?
What?
我以为他没生育能力呢
I didn't think he had it in him!
我明白
I know, right?
这不是件好笑的事情
Right, this is no laughing matter.
当然不是
No, it's not.
保利事实上做的很棒
And Paulie is actually great.
在椅子上
In chair.
你想过给人收养吗?
You were thinking about adoption?
对  有对夫妇不能生育
Yeah, there's this couple.
你必须知道  他们已经努力了5年
They've been trying to have a kid for five years.
是我在《Penny Saver》杂志看到的
We found them in the Penny Saver next to the exotic birds.
他们有律师了  而我们约好下周末见面
They have a legitimate lawyer and I was going to go meet with them next weekend.
朱诺  这是件很难决定
Junebug, that is a tough, tough thing to do.
并超过你能理解的事情
Probably tougher than you can understand right now.
我明白
I know...
只是我还没准备好做个妈妈
...It's just that I'm not ready to be a mom.
见鬼  你当然还没
Damn skippy, you're not!
你甚至都记不得给妹妹吃哮喘药
You don't even remember to give Liberty Bell her breathing meds.
就一次而已  而且想想至少她并没死掉
That was once! And she did not die, if you recall!
亲爱的  你有想过其他选择吗?
Honey, had you considered, you know, the alternative?
没有
No.
你可真是勇敢无比啊
Well, you're a little Viking!
先做首要的事
First things first,
要让你保持健康
we have to get you healthy.
你需要吃孕妇维他命
You need prenatal vitamins,
而且它对你的指甲也很有好处
Incidentally, they do incredible things for your nails, so that's a plus.
还有约个医生检查
Oh, and we need to schedule a doctor's appointment.
看看你什么时候生产
Figure out where you're going to deliver.
我要和你去见那对夫妇
Juno, I'm coming with you to meet this adoption people.
你还是个小孩子  我不想宝宝被不好的人收养
You're just a kid. I don't want you to get ripped off by a couple of babystarved wingnuts.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
我还以为你是个懂事的孩子
I thought you were the kind of girl who knew when to say when.
我真不清楚自己是个怎样的女孩子
I don't really know what kind of girl I am.
跟我说实话  是我的过失吗?
Tell it to me straight, Bren. Do you think this is my fault?
小孩如果无所事事  就会发生这样的事情
I think kids get bored and have intercourse.
而且朱朱对此也没有自控力
And I think Junebug was a dummy about it, Mac.
我还没准备好当个爷爷
I am not ready to be a Pop- Pop.
你不会当个爷爷
You're not going to be a Pop- Pop.
有人会在这个烂摊子上
Somebody else is going to find a precious blessing
得到上帝的祝福
from Jesus in this garbage dump of a situation.
当她站在我们面前时  你就料到这件事了吗?
Did you see that coming when she sat us down here?
对  不过我倒希望是被学校开除了  或者是嗑药之类
Yeah. But I was hoping she was expelled or into hard drugs.
我也这样想  酒后驾车什么的  可没想到会是这样
That was my first instinct too. Or D.W.I. Anything but this.
下次我看到里克  我要狠狠教训他
And I'm going to punch that Bleeker kid in the weiner the next time I see him.
麦克  你知道这不是他想的
Mac, no. You know it wasn't his idea.
你好  我是瓦内萨  两位是朱诺和麦高夫先生
Hi! I'm Vanessa. You must be Juno and Mr. MacGuff.
瓦内萨・罗琳
Vanessa.
你是瓦内萨本人对吗?
It's Vanessa, right?
谢谢招待我和我这个不俏女
Thanks for having me and my irresponsible child over to your house.
不  得谢谢你们
Oh no. Thank you.
谢谢
请进吧
Come on in.
要我帮你拿下外衣和帽子吗?
Can I take your coat or your hat?
噢  好的  谢谢
Oh, yeah, sure, thanks.
你们在杂志的照片很真实
Wicked pic in the Penny Saver, by the way. Super classy.
不像其他人假树林作背景的照片
Not like those people with fake woods in the background,
说实话  那用来唬弄谁啊?!
Honestly, who do they think they're fooling?
你在《Penny Saver》上看到我们的?
You found us in the Penny Saver?
你好  我是她丈夫马克・罗琳
Hi. Mark Loring. I'm the husband.
-你好吗?  我是麦克・麦高夫  -很高兴认识你
- How you doing? Mac McGuff. - Nice to meet you.
你好
Hi.
她是吉托・拉斯  我们代表律师
This is Gerta Rauss, our attorney.
吉托・拉斯
Gerta Rauss.
你好  很高兴认识你
Hi, pleased to meet you.
当然了  她就是朱诺
And this, of course, is Juno.
听起来像阿拉斯加的小城市
Like the city in Alaska.
不
No.
不是吗?
No?
好
Hon?
亲爱的  你不要坐吗?
Shall we sit down and get to know one another?
我打算拿点喝的
I thought I'd get some drinks.
喝点什么?  有苏打水  维他矿泉水和橙汁
What would anyone like? I have Pellegrino or Vitamin Water or orange juice.
来杯波本威士忌  谢谢
A Maker's Mark, please. Up.
她有点
She's kidding.
她有点小幽默感  是她的天赋之一
Junebug has a wonderful sense of humor, just one of her many genetic gifts.
我坐好了
I see.
那么  朱诺  你进展到什么阶段了?
So, Juno. First off, how far along are you?
我在读高中
I'm a junior.
我意思是指怀孕
No, I mean in your pregnancy.
我的后妈昨天带我检查
Oh. Uh, actually my stepmom took me yesterday
医生说有三个月了
to the doctor and they said I was twelve weeks.
不错啊
Oh, that's marvelous.
所以你在读第二学期(美国高中三学期制  一个学期三个月)
So you're into your second trimester?
对  很明显
Yeah, apparently.
我上了五个月了
I'm due on May 4.
很好
Great.
我朋友说(怀孕)头两三个月是最辛苦的
My girlfriends tell me the first couple months are the hardest.
我自己没多大感觉
I didn't notice it at all.
我比较关心的是  要在牛仔裤外头穿件松紧裤
I'm more concerned about when they have to put that elastic band in the front of my jeans.
我想怀孕是件美不可言的事
I think pregnancy is beautiful.
你该庆幸自己没怀孕
Well, you're lucky it's not you.
我们谈谈怎么处理这个
So, let's talk how we're gonna do this... thing.
谈什么?  把它挤出来
Well, don't I just have the thing?
然后递给你就行
Squeeze it on out and hand it over?
马克和瓦内萨商议过了  决定采取公开收养的方式
Mark and Vanessa are willing to negotiate an open adoption.
那是什么意思?
What does that mean?
就是收养后定期给你们反馈  比如宝宝照片
It means they'd send annual updates, photos,
让你们了解宝宝成长过程
let Juno know how the baby is doing as he or she grows up.
不要  我不想看到  任何照片反馈什么
Whoah. I don't want photos or any kind of notification.
我意思是不能按老一套方法做吗?
Can't we just kick this old school?
把宝宝放在篮子
I stick the baby in a basket and send it your way.
就像芦苇丛里的摩西
Like Moses in the reeds.
那是旧约《圣经》里的做法
Technically, that would be kickin' it Old Testament.
对  说的对
Exactly! Right?
你明白我意思
Do you know what I mean?
就像古时做法  快捷又省事
Like in the good old days. When it was quick and dirty.
好吧  大家都同意采用传统收养方式
Well, then we all agree a traditional closed adoption would be best for all involved?
我靠  就这样  秘密收养
Shit, yes, just close her on up.
我们会补偿你一切医疗费用
Obviously, we would compensate you for all your medical expenses.
还需要我们其它方面的补偿吗?
Are you looking for any other type of compensation?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
不
No.
不  我又不是在出售"东西"
No, I don't want to sell the thing, I just...
我只想
I want...
我只想这个宝宝有人愿意爱它
I just want the baby to be with people who are gonna love it,
有对爱它的父母  好吗?
And be good parents, you know?
我只是个高中女生
I'm in high school.
伙计  我还没有准备好呢
I'm ill- equipped.
你正做着一件最美妙  最无私的事
You're doing a beautiful and a selfless thing for us.
瓦内萨从结婚开始就一直想做个妈妈
Vanessa has wanted a baby ever since we got married.
我太想要个孩子了
I want to be a mommy so badly!
看得出来
You don't say.
你不觉得人生下来就有其使命吗?
Have you ever felt like you were just born to do something?
对
Yes.
我就是为修空调而生的
Heating and air conditioning.
你说的没错
There you go.
我的天职就是做个母亲
I was born to be a mother.
这是我相信的
Some of us are.
你怎么样马克?  你天生就做个父亲吗?
How about you, Mark, are you looking forward to being a dad?
那是  当然
Betcha, yeah.
全世界男人都想当个父亲  做足球队教练
Every guy wants to be a father. Wants to coach the soccer team and
或者做一些科学工程研究  比如火山爆发  之类的
help out with the science fair and the volcano goes off.
太多了
Yeah, all that.
或者给你们看看起草好的协议吧
Maybe Gerta could take us through the preliminary documents that you have drawn up.
好的  但是能不能用下洗手间  怀孕让我总想去尿尿
Could I use the facilities first? Being pregnant makes me pee like Seabiscuit.
当然  楼下的卫生间改掉了  你可以用楼上房间里的
The downstairs bathroom is being re- tiled, but if you go upstairs, then to the right...
有马桶的房间  明白
Oh yeah! Room with the toilet.
她还好吧?
Is she alright?
嘿  抱歉
Sorry.
嘿  伙计  没想到你也上来了
Sorry, I didn't expect to see you up here.
我上来拿点东西
I just came up to get something.
你老婆叫你监视我?
Did your wife send you up here to spy on me?
不是
No.
我们看起来像患了妄想症的雅痞吗?
Do we come off as paranoid yuppies or something?
我偷喷了点你老婆的香水
I stole a squirt of your wife's perfume.
真的?
Really?
闻起来会很开心
It's Clinique Happy.
闻一下  感受一下这个香味
Get a whiff of those sparkling topnotes!
这些可以让我感到  开心?
Is that supposed to make me feel happy?
你当然应该感到开心  老弟
You should feel happy, Holmes.
我会给你和瓦内萨一个生命作礼物  吃喝拉哭呀
I'm giving you and Vanessa the gift of life. Sweet, screaming, pooping life!
而且你们也看不到它被包着
And you don't even have to be there when it comes out all covered in...
看到什么?
Viscera?
血乎乎的生出来
Blood and guts.
那是Les Paul?  (著名吉它品牌吉普森)
Is that a Les Paul?
是的  没错
Yes, it is.
瓦内萨把那个房间留给我用
Vanessa gave me my own room for all my stuff.
她留给你整间屋中的  一间房来放你的东西?
She gave you your own room in your whole house for your stuff?
她人真好  不是吗?  马克
She's got you on a long leash there, Mark.
哦  太美了
Oh, it's beautiful.
知道吗  我一直认为吉普森吉他比芬达的好的多
You know? I always loved Gibson way more than Fender.
你弹什么的?
What do you play?
我弹和弦啊
I rock a Harmony.
这是什么?  红木做的?
So is it mahagony?
这个柄弄断了咋办?
What happens if you crack the neck?
你知道弄坏了会有什么后果
Tell me about it. I used to play in this really tight
我以前在芝加哥加入过一个乐队
band when I lived in Chicago and one night we opened up
有晚为Melvins乐队暖场弄坏了
for the Melvins and I busted that thing right on
花了我800多块
stage and it cost me $800 just to get it fixed.
那是在什么
When was that?
93年  摇滚的巅峰年代
'93. Best time for rock and roll.
应该是77年啊  (93年)朋克专辑是最热的
Nuh- uh, '77! Punk Volume #1.
你疯了
You're crazy.
你那时在场?
You weren't there,
你不会懂朋克的魔力
You couldn't understand the magic.
你还未出生呢
You weren't even alive!
那是什么?
What's that?
我的普拉提机
It's a Pilates machine.
你用这个干嘛?
What do you make with it?
没什么  是个锻炼器械而已
You don't make anything. It's for exercising.
我老婆看电视订购了类似的
My wife ordered one of those
一个健身电视栏目
Tony Little Gazelles off the TV.
那个扎着马尾巴辫子的推销员
You know, from the guy with the ponytail?
我怎么都看他不顺眼
That guy just doesn't look right to me.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
抱歉
Excuse me.
嗨
Hi.
你们在交流音乐啊
You're playing music?
朱诺想弹一弹"金宝"
Juno wanted a little closer look at Kimber.
你的吉它叫金宝?
Your guitar is named Kimber?
对
Yeah.
名字很酷  我以前那个叫罗斯福
That's cool. My axe is named Roosevelt.
现在的叫富兰克林  但我想改更辣的名如波丽雅
After Franklin, not Ted. He was the hot one with polio.
我们能下楼去吗?  我们还有
Gerta is downstairs, we still have
还有很多事情要讨论
a lot of stuff to go over.
给我来拿吧
I got it.
我不想打断你们
Not to interrupt the jam session.
仔细看看  如有问题的话就打电话给我
So, just look these over and if you have any questions, call me at my office.
我们真的非常感谢
We would really appreciate it if you would
还请你随时保持联系
just keep us updated on any doctor's appointments,
告诉我们进展  如果不麻烦的话
Ultrasounds, anything of that nature.
当然不  我知道  我会告诉你们的
For sure. You want to know how your kid is cooking, I get it.
你确信要这么做了?
You think you're really going to do this, then?
当然  我喜欢你们
Yeah. I like you guys.
你有多确信呢?
How sure would you say you are?
是80%呢还是90%呢?
Would you say you're 80% sure, 90% sure?
我会说104%确信
I'm going to say I'm about 104% sure.
真的?
Really?
如果我现在就可把这"东西"给你们  我会毫不犹豫
Seriously, if I could just have the thing and give it to you now, I totally would,
不过我猜他现在像是只盐水虾般
But I'm guessing it looks probably like a Sea Monkey right now,
至少得等他长的可爱一点吧
And we should let it get a little cuter, right?
-是的  -很好
- Yeah. - Great.
说的对
Keep it in the oven.
这个主意不错
I think that's a great idea.
很高兴认识你们
Nice to meet you both.
-我也是  -路上当心  希望很快有好消息
Please, drive carefully. Hopefully we'll hear from you soon.
-保重  -再见
- Take care. - Buh bye.
冬天来了
嘿  伙计
Hey, man.
嘿  维惴  好吗?
Hey, Vijay.
你听说没有  朱诺・麦高夫怀孕
Did you hear Juno MacGuff is pregnant?
有
Yeah.
-就好像我们妈妈和老师那样  -对
- Like our moms and teachers! - Yeah.
他们说是你的种?
Did you hear it's yours?
对
Yup.
太不幸了伙计
What a trip, man.
我自己都不知道怎么回事
I don't really know too much about it.
你为什么不留胡子呢?
You should grow a moustache.
长不出来
I can't.
我也是
Me neither.
我决定不穿内裤了
But I'm going to stop wearing underpants.
我的精子活力在下降  再见
Raise my sperm count.
朱诺
Juno, hey.
嘿  保利
Hey, Bleek.
我们一会儿去看电影一边吃甜甜圈
Me and some guys are gonna go to the movies after school and
电影里那个家伙有18个孩子
we're gonna donut that flick with the guy who has eighteen kids.
你跟我们一起去吗?
Do you want to come?
听起来主意不错  但我要去做超声波
Sounds awesome, but I got my ultrasound.
哦  是吗?
Oh, really?
我能不能
Can I...
需要我陪你吗?
Should I come?
你不能把这些甜甜圈都浪费了
Oh, you can't waste those donut balls,
或者我可以晚一会儿去
But maybe I could drop by later.
好的
Okay, cool.
-再见保利  -再见
- Later, Bleek. - See ya.
我会帮你留个座
I'll save you a seat.
这就是你的宝宝
There's your baby.
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my God.
那个是手
There's a hand.
这里是胳膊
And an arm.
脚在这儿
And there's the feet.
朱诺  看到你的宝宝吗?
Would you look at that?
哦  快看那大脑袋  伙计  真是吓人哦
Check out Baby Big- Head. Dude, that thing is freaky looking!
不好意思
Excuse me, I am a sacred vessel.
我不就像个神圣的皮囊装了个人吗?
All you've got in your stomach is Taco Bell!
真奇怪你们犯得着  这样激动流泪吗?
It's amazing that there's actually saps that cry at this.
说什么呢?  我可不是铁石心肠的人
What? I'm not made of stone.
好了  结束了
Well, there you have it.
你们想知道性别吗?
Would you like to know the sex?
-好  -不
- Yes. - No.
-拜托了  -不行  绝对不要
- Please, Junebug? - No sex.
准备出生的时候来个惊喜?
Planning to be surprised when you deliver?
是的  我希望给马克和瓦内萨一个惊喜
I want Mark and Vanessa to be surprised,
假如你告诉了我们就不好保守秘密了
and if you told me, I'll just ruin everything.
马克和瓦内萨是你学校的同学?
Are Mark and Vanessa your friends at school?
不是  他们是孩子准养父母
No, they're the adoptive parents.
哦  太好了  真是谢天谢地
Oh. Well, thank goodness for that.
你这话是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
我在这里看过很多未成年妈妈
I just see a lot of teenage mothers come through here.
这种环境下对孩子成长太有害了
It's obviously a poisonous environment to raise a baby in.
你怎么就知道我做得很差呢?
How do you know that I'm so poisonous?
你怎么知道那些养父母就不是恋童癖呢?
What if these adoptive parents turn out to be evil molesters?
和假冒的夫妇
Or like stage parents.
他们可能完全不合格!
They could be utterly negligent. Maybe they'll do a far shittier job
可能我继女更懂得抚养
of raising a kid than my dumbass stepdaughter ever would.
你想过吗?
Have you considered that?
我想没有
No, I guess not.
你的工作头衔叫什么?
What is your job title, exactly?
我是个超声波技师  女士
I'm an ultrasound technician, ma'am.
我是个美甲师  我觉得我们应该先管好自己的工作
Well I'm a nail technician, and I think we both ought to stick to what we know.
你的意思是?
Excuse me?
你以为坐在那拍个片就很拽吗?
You think you're so special because you get to play Picture Pages up there?
我五岁的女儿都能做得好
My five year- old daughter could do that,
她还不是最聪明的那个呢
and let me tell you, she is not the brightest bulb in the tanning bed.
你不如回去夜校读些有用课程  学点真本事吧
So why don't you go back to night school in Manteno and learn a real trade!
布伦  你酷毙了
Bren, you's a dick!
爱死你了
I love it.
朱诺  噢  没料到是你啊
Juno? Wow, I didn't expect to see you here.
我有些好东西要给你们看看  瓦内萨在家吗?
I have something really cool to show you guys. Is Vanessa here?
哦她不在  她今晚要加班加点
No, actually she's working late tonight.
然后省出时间来
She's trying to accrue as much time off as she can before...
对  她得腾出时间来
Oh right. I hear these are quite the time- suck.
快进来吧  我有人参果汁
Wanna come in? I was just having a Ginseng Cooler.
要喝点吗?
Would you like one?
这些就是富人喝的东西吧?
What is it with you rich people and your herb- infused juices?
因为我们和这44盒装的饮品有缘分
It's probably got something to do with those forty four- packs they come in.
它们味道不错啊
They're not bad, though.
为什么你不工作?
Why aren't you at work?
我在家里工作  我是个作曲家
I work mostly from home. I'm a composer.
哦  我靠
No shit.
就像约翰内斯・勃拉姆斯(德国名作曲家)?
Like Johannes Brahms?
不是  更商业点的
No, more commercial stuff.
例如呢?
Like what?
广告歌曲
Commercials.
你看过凯胜男用除臭机广告吗?
Have you seen the ads for the Titanium Power men's deodorant?
对  这个厨房就是靠这广告挣的
Paid for this kitchen.
赚得好啊!
You're quite the sellout, Mark.
Melvins乐队该说什么好呢?
What would the Melvins say?
你不是说有东西要给我看吗?
Did you say you had something to show me.
注意了先生  你未来的宝宝
Behold, good sir! Your future child.
嘿  让我看看
Hey, look at that.
我猜会和我朋友保利有点像
I think it looks like my friend Paulie.
他是个光头的?
Is he also bald and amorphous?
他是爸爸
No, he's the dad.
你知道是男孩还是女孩?
Can you tell if it's a boy or a girl?
我可以要求  医生也知道  不过我想留个惊喜
I can't, the doctor can. But I kind of want it to be a surprise.
就这么两个可能
Well, it can only go one of two ways.
随你怎么想了
That's what you think.
我可是能豪饮啊  所以可能生个不男不女的
I drink tons of booze so you might end up with
还缺胳膊少腿
one of those scary neuter- babies that's born without junk.
缺胳膊少腿?
Junk, huh?
对  缺胳膊少腿
You know, it's parts.
我知道是什么
I know what junk is.
嗯
Yeah, right.
我们可要四肢健全的啊  拜托了
We definitely want it to have some junk, please.
你不用担心
Well, you don't need to worry about a thing.
我继母照让我吃得超级健康
My stepmom, Bren, makes me eat super healthy.
我连微波炉前都不能站
I can't stand in front of the microwave and no red M&Ms.
或者吃M&M的巧克力豆  我倒希望你真的准备好了
I hope you're ready.
哦  听到了吗?
Ooh... do you hear that?
什么?
What?
这是我最喜爱的歌曲
This is my favorite song.
音速青年乐队的《巨星》专辑  翻唱卡朋特乐队的曲子
It's Sonic Youth doing "Superstar" by the Carpenters.
是的  我知道卡朋特
Oh, yeah, yeah, I know the Carpenters.
女人鼓手和古怪男人  和白线乐队风格相象
Chick drummer, freaky dude. Not unlike the White Stripes.
对  你不会听过这种风格的卡朋特
You haven't heard the Carpenters like this. Just listen.
对  我喜欢这个
Yeah, I like this.
你说你最喜欢的乐队是哪个?
What did you say your favorite band was?
是斯徒奇  派迪史密斯和逃离乐队的结合
Didn't. It's a three- way tie between the Stooges, Patti Smith and the Runaways.
我给你听一些我最喜爱的CD  毕竟你肚子里有我的孩子
I definitely need to make you some CDs. At least while my kid's in there.
《血之魔术师》?
The Wizard of Gore?
戈登路易斯  恐怖片大师的杰作
That is Herschel Gordon Lewis. He's the ultimate master of horror.
拜托  达里欧・阿基多  才是真正的恐怖片大师
Please. Dario Argento is so the ultimate master of horror.
阿基多?
Argento?
他也不错  但是路易斯的风格是完全神经错乱
He's alright, but Lewis is completely dimented.
一大堆的粘液  全是红色的糖浆
We're talking buckets of goo.
还有放在阴阳图上的人造大脑
Red corn syrup all over the place. Fake brains coming out the yin- yang.
实话说吧  这片有点傻叉
Quite frankly, this looks a little stupid.
碟片给我
Give me the tape.
这片比得上阿基多的《阴风阵阵》
This is even better than Suspiria.
我告诉过你的
What'd I tell ya?
伙计  你看恐怖片还真的挺有品位
You have decent taste in slasher movies.
小小兴趣而已
Here's to dovetailing interests.
你们给宝宝起名字了吗?
Have you guys thought of any names for the baby yet?
算是有吧  如果是女儿  瓦内萨希望叫麦迪逊
Sort of, yes. Vanessa likes Madison for a girl.
麦迪逊?  等等
Madison?
这听起来  很断背的感觉?!
Isn't that a little, gay?
哦  难道大家都得起个  古老神秘的名字叫"朱诺"?
Well, pretentious much? Should everyone just have a mysterious name like Juno?
知道吗  我老爸对古罗马和古希腊的神话很着迷
My dad went through this huge obsession with Roman and Greek mythology.
所以他决定用宙斯老婆的名字给我命名
He decided to name me after Zeus's wife,
宙斯很花心  不过我肯定  朱诺是他唯一的妻子
Zeus had tons of lays, but I'm pretty sure Juno was his only wife.
而且她很漂亮  就和黛安娜王妃一样
She was supposed to be really beautiful but really mean. Like Diana Ross.
嗯  很适合你
That suits you.
谢谢?!
Thanks?
你挺特别的
You're something else.
瓦内萨回来了  你得走了
Vanessa. You'd better go.
她不喜欢看到我"无所作为"地看恐怖片
She hates when I sit around watching movies and I don't contribute.
我来告诉她  我总能让人信服
I'll handle this. I'm really good at diffusing mom- type rage.
不  朱诺  不
No, Juno, no.
嘿朱诺  怎么了?
Juno, what's going on?
-没什么  -你来这里干嘛?  出什么事情了?
- Nothing. - What are you doing here? What's wrong?
只是我今天去看医生了
Nothing, I went to the doctor today.
宝宝有问题?
Is there something wrong with the baby?
宝宝很健康
The baby is great.
什么都正常  还看到了它的脚趾头
It's the right size and everything. I even saw its phalanges today!
看看吧
Here.
是个宝宝
It's the baby.
你的宝宝
It's your baby.
感觉它好像在招手
It kinda looks like it's waving.
"嘿瓦内萨  你愿意做我妈妈吗?"
Like it's saying "Hey, Vanessa. Will you be my mom?"
太不可思议了
Yeah, it kind of does.
朱诺  特地把片子拿过来给我们看
Juno was nice enough to bring that over for us today.
对  刚抹掉肚子上的超声波液  我就赶来了
I came as soon as I got that ultrasound goo off my pelvis.
真是难以置信
It was crazy actually,
我继母还为此  和B超检查师吵了一架
My stepmom verbally abused the ultrasound tech so we got escorted off the premises.
看看你们都买了一大堆的东西
Wow, what kind of swag did you score?
准妈妈购物狂
Mall madness, huh?
只是为宝宝准备的一些东西而已
It's just some stuff I picked up for the baby.
宝宝受洗礼时等别人送就行了
Don't you usually get all that stuff at a baby shower?
我后妈怀着我妹时  亲友送了一屋子礼物
When my stepmom was pregnant with my little sister she got a million gifts.
不过我一点也不嫉妒  因为那些东西超级烂
But I wasn't jealous 'cause they all were super lame.
我怀疑没有人会送礼物
I doubt anyone's gonna throw us a shower.
为什么呢?
Why wouldn't they throw you a baby shower?
我不知道该怎么说
I don't think people know how to feel about this situation
因为事情并还不是板上钉钉
because it's not set in stone.
你的意思是?
What isn't set...
不不不  你该不会认为我会最后关头退出吧?
You don't think I'm going to flake out on you?
不是这个意思
No, I don't, Juno.
我们曾经历过那样的情况
We went through a situation before
最后都不成事
where it didn't work out.
对  恐惧后遗症
Cold feet.
哦  你们该去中国
You should have gone to China.
他们送小孩如送免费iPod
I hear they give away babies like free iPods.
好像把宝宝放到礼炮里
They put 'em in those T- shirt guns
然后以40秒速  "砰"的打出去
and shoot them out at sporting events.
你父母现在可能在担心你在哪里
Your parents are probably wondering where you are.
我已经都怀孕了
Naah. I'm already pregnant,
死猪不怕开水烫了  对吧?
so what other kind of shenanigans could I get into?
不过  我也该走了
I should probably bounce.
别忘了你的包
Hey, don't forget your bag.
谢了
Ah, bag!
好的  保重
Okay, take care.
你哪儿去了朱朱?
Where the hell have you been, Junebug?
我给马克和瓦内萨看超声波结果
I just drove to St. Cloud to show Mark and Vanessa the ultrasound.
在他家呆了一会
I ended up staying for a couple of hours.
一会?  你干嘛直接就去他们哪儿了?
A couple of hours? Why are you going over there in the first place?
不是说好随时告诉宝宝最新情况吗?  所以我就去了
They wanted to know about this stuff. I said I'd keep them updated, so I did!
那你也可以邮寄给他们啊
You could have mailed it to them.
你干嘛自己开车去那个什么  地方?
Why would you drive an hour out to East Jesus, Nowhere?
我就是这么做了
I don't know, I just did.
在等瓦内萨回来时
And while Mark and I were waiting for Vanessa,
我和马克一起看了《血之魔术师》
we watched The Wizard of Gore,
他给我录了一些很拉风的CD
And he burned me a couple of CDs of this weird music.
很酷  不错
He's kind of cool.
朱诺  你不能就这样去马克那儿的
Juno, you can't just drop in on them like that.
这没什么大不了的  他们也没什么呀
No, it was not a big deal. He was totally cool with it.
你不了解
You don't understand.
马克是有妇之夫你们要保持距离
Mark is a married man, there are boundaries.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
听着
Listen,
布伦
Bren- duhhh.
听起来好像是你要面对这一切
You're acting like you're the one who has to go through this
好像是你挺着个大肚为别人生孩子
and get huge and shove a baby out of your vag for someone else.
他是有妇之夫怎么了?
What does it even matter if he's married?
我有很多朋友都结婚了
I can have friends that are married.
没那么简单的小姑娘
It doesn't work that way, kiddo.
你根本不了解婚姻
You don't know squat about the dynamics of marriage.
你根本不了解我
You don't know anything about me!
我对你足够了解
I know enough.
我们根本就没有狗呢!
We don't even have a dog!
对  因为你对它们的口水过敏
Yeah, because you're allergic to their saliva.
我为你牺牲了很多  朱诺  过几年你不在这里住了
I have sacrificed a lot for you, Juno. But in a couple years when you move out
我就会养几条魏玛犬的
I'm going to get Weimaraners.
哦  痴人说梦啊!
Wow, dream big!
滚得远点!
Oh, go fly a kite.
嘿朱诺
Hi, Juno.
有什么要帮忙的吗?
What can I do for you?
保利在家吗?
Bleeker home?
保利的妈妈以前可能是个"辣妹"
Bleeker's mom was possibly attractive once.
现在倒像"腊霉"(又肥又丑)
But now she looks a hobbit.
你知道就像电影里的哈比人
You know, the fat one that was in The Goonies.
嘿  伙计
Hey, man,
干嘛这么用心  我都闻到你头发冒烟了
Don't concentrate so hard. I think I can smell your hair all burning.
有什么事吗?
Hey, what's up?
没事  只是
Not much, I just wanted to come say hey.
怀念以前晚上约会的时光
I miss hanging out with you on school nights.
那些橙味跳跳糖是保利唯一的怪癖
Orange Tic- Tacs are Bleeker's one and only vice.
我怀孕的那晚  他嘴的味道犹如甜甜的糖果
The day I got pregnant, his mouth tasted really tangy and delicious.
感觉怎么样?  看起来
You seem to be getting...
你变的像个孕妇了
...pregnant- er these days.
你知道我找了一对收养的父母
Ya know, I set up this whole private adoption...
住在库洛区的一对夫妇  他们很适合做养父母
and this married couple in Saint Cloud are going to be the parents.
真的
Really?
他们看起来怎么样?
What are they like?
哦  那个男的很不错
The guy, he's awesome.
他叫马克
His name is Mark and
他喜欢看老恐怖电影  弹吉它
he likes old horror movies and he plays the guitar.
事实上  下午我们一直在一起
We actually hung out this afternoon.
没问题吗?
Is that normal?
或许不吧  不过
Probably not, but...
听着  我和我爸爸和布伦说了  他们不会跟你家人说的
I talked to dad and Bren and they said they wouldn't narc you out to your folks,
不用担心
So,
放轻松就行了
I think we should be cool.
我觉得轻松多了
That's a relief.
我现在看起来
I'm gonna start looking
像只大胖狗
like a pretty big dork soon.
你还会觉得我可爱吗?
Will you still think I'm cute when I'm huge?
我一直觉得你很可爱
I always think you're cute.
你很迷人
I think you're beautiful.
老天!  保利
Jeez, Bleek.
真的
I do.
朱诺  等这一切过去  我们一起重组乐队
Hey Junebug, when this is all over we should get the band back together.
对  应该要
Yeah.
这个主意不错
That would be awesome.
我是说重组以后我们整个队
Once Tino gets a new drumhead
可以一起摇滚了
we're just, like, ready to rock.
而且  我觉得我们也可以重新一起
We could always get back together too.
看你了
That's an option.
我们在一起过吗?
Were we together?
是啊  你知道
Yeah, we were once.
有那么一次
That time.
卡特里娜怎么样?
What about Katrina De Voort?
你可以和她一起呀
You could totally go out with Katrina De Voort.
我不喜欢卡特里娜  她闻起来有股肉汤味
I don't like Katrina.
你没闻到过?
She smells like soup.
她的整个房间闻起来都有肉汤味
Her whole house smells of soup.
好了
Okay.
现在可以选择奶油色或者奶酪色
So we have Custard, Cheesecake.
都是黄色
They're yellow.
我想用这些比较中性的自然色
I wanted to pick something that was gender- neutral until
然后可以加一些其它的什么
we get the baby and then we can add a more decisive palette.
你认为黄色是中性自然色?
Why does everyone think yellow is gender- neutral?
我所认识的人里  没有把房间涂成黄色的
I don't know any guy with a yellow bedroom.
我觉得这个色度的奶油色不错
I'm thinking more Custard with this light.
或许我们应该先小部分试一下
I don't know. Maybe I should paint a larger swatch...
为什么我们不能等几个月?
Or you could wait a few more months.
反正宝宝又不会现在  出现要求刷成沙漠的颜色
It's not like the baby's going to storm in here demanding dessert- colored walls.
《期待》说宝宝房间对妈妈来说很重要
"What to Expect" says that readying the baby's room is an important process for the woman.
尤其是收养妈妈  术名叫"安巢"
Especially if you're adopting. It's called "nesting. "
"安巢"?
Nesting?
你要用口水树枝搭个巢吗?
Are you going to build the crib out of sticks and spit?
我想你应该看看那本书  讲父亲角色那章我做了标记
You should read the book. I flagged the "daddy chapters" for you.
我觉得现在漆墙太早了
I think it's too early to paint.
我就是这么想的
That's my opinion.
我不同意
I disagree.
这个墙上也要放点东西
This wall is going to need something.
挂一幅全家福照片
Our first family photo right in the middle.
就在正中间
Right up there.
想象得到吗?
Can you see it?
这甜甜圈吃起来味道很棒
Yum! This pretzel tastes like a friggin' donut!
给我尝尝
Share the love, sweetness!
不给
You can't have any.
停下
She's assaulting me!
我喘不过气来了
She's denying me fresh- baked goodness!
哦  天哪!
Oh, my God.
那个是瓦内萨
That's her. That's Vanessa Loring.
杂志上找的那个收养者?
Of the Penny Saver Lorings?
姐妹  她看起来很正点啊
Dude, she's, like, really pretty.
感觉你很吃惊啊
You sound totally shocked or something.
她好象是要把那个小宝宝偷走做收藏品
She's totally gonna steal that kid for her collection.
对  很像
Right, seriously.
无聊啊
Boring!
我想我可以吃一大块曲奇饼干  外加卷着的大块羊肉
I could so go for a huge cookie right now with like, a lamb kebab, simultaneously.
你怎好像饿死鬼投胎一样
God, Spermy. Must you always feed?
好象永无止境地吃
It's like, never- ending for you.
朱诺!
Juno!
嗨!  瓦内萨
Hi, Vanessa!
你来这里干嘛?
What brings you to the mall today?
逛街  那边是我的一些女朋友
I was just shopping with my girlfriends.
你是女同性恋?
You're gay?
对不起她开玩笑的
No.
没事
Just ignore her.
你感觉怎么样?
Well, how are you feeling?
很好  一切都很好
Great! Everything's stupendous.
哦  肚脐眼像个按扭
Oh, coming in on that snooze button.
太不可思议了
That's incredible.
天哪
Oh, God.
怎么了?
What?
它在踢我
Kicking away.
我可以  摸一下吗?
Could I feel it?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
在学校里所有的人  都来摸我的肚子的  疯狂极了
At school everyone's just grabbing my belly all the time.
我是个传奇人物了  他们都叫我大鲸鱼的
I'm a legend. They call me the Cautionary Whale.
我什么都感觉不到
I can't feel anything.
它不是为我而动
It's not moving for me.
你应该试试和它讲话
You should try talking to it.
因为它能听见你的  虽然可能听起来很遥远
They can hear you, even though it's all ten thousand leagues under the sea.
嘿  宝宝
Hi, baby.
我  我是瓦内萨
It's me. It's Vanessa.
我很想见你  迫不及待
I can't wait to meet you.
你能听见我说话吗宝贝?
Can you hear me, baby?
我的天使
Sweet angel?
我能感觉到
I felt it!
太神奇了!
That was magical.
谢谢
Thank you.
春天到了
你好
Hello?
"你好"
Hey!
我最近在听你给我的那几张CD
So, I've been listening to that really weird CD that you made me.
有什么感想?
Yeah? What's the verdict?
很可爱
Well, it's cute.
很可爱?
It's cute?
假如听惯了Iggy和Stooges的摇滚
When you're used to listening to the raw power of Iggy and the Stooges,
那其他音乐比起来都会显得软软的
everything else just sounds kind of precious in comparison.
或许你听了一堆的卡朋特  唱片来支持你的观点
I imagine you have a collection of punk chestnuts to prove your point.
那
Well...
想想你接受过专业音乐的熏陶啊
...consider it your musical education.
我等不及你会教我点什么
I can't wait to see what you've got to teach me.
有什么  你还是继续工作吧
Stop surfing porn and get back to work.
我只是打来问问好
Just wanted to call and say hi.
那谢谢了
Go learn something.
-我感觉像是去墨西哥旅行  -还去了希腊和中国
- Oh, a little trip down Mexico way. - And Greece and China apparently.
你已经怀孕几个月了?
How many months has it been now?
肚子越来越大了
You're getting huge.
八个月了  你肯定不会相信  我裸体时的样子有多么怪异
It's homing in on the eight. You should see how weird I look naked.
我真希望我的乳房能大点
I wish my funbags would get bigger.
相信我你不会的  事实上  我现在不得不戴胸罩
Trust me, you don't. I have to actually wear a friggin' bra now
还要全身都擦上恶心的可可油  免得皮肤松弛过度
and rub all this nasty cocoa butter stuff on myself so my skin won't explode.
真火辣!
Hot!
为什么全世界都盯着我看啊?
Why is everyone always staring at me?
还不是因为你的肚子像个几何形状了
Well, you are kind of convex, you know?
哇!  是吗?  你什么时候做了几何学达人?
Whoah! Who's been doing their geometry homework for once!
我别无选择  基德的身影总是在我眼前晃
I have no choice. Keith has been grading me so hard lately.
-别直呼康纳老师为基德好吗?  -为什么?
Do not call Mr. Conyers "Keith".
恶心啊  因为我的孕妇呕吐症现在超强烈
'Cause my barf reflex is really enheightened these days.
基德很野性
But Keith's hot.
他满脸胡喳
Eww, he's all beardy!
你听说里克要和卡特里娜一起参加舞会吗?
Did you hear that Bleek is going to the prom with Katrina De Voort?
卡特里娜?
Katrina?
不可能  他一点也不喜欢她
No way, he doesn't like Katrina.
他一定是出于怜悯之心
Must be like a pity date or something.
我听说是他主动的  先去本哈拿餐馆
I heard he asked her and that the're going to Benihana,
然后去舞会  最后去维惴家的小屋
and then prom, and then Vijay's parents' cabin.
他跟我说她家有股肉汤味
He told me that Katrina's house smells like soup!
老天啊  的确是如此
Oh my God, it totally does.
四年前我去她家参加生日派对时  那味道是够恶心的
I was there four years ago for her birthday party and it was like Lipton Landing.
但是你知道男孩子  为了做爱什么都做得出来?
But you know, boys have endured way worse things for nookie.
哦  得了吧
Oh, please.
他们根本不可能发生关系的
There is no way that they're having sex,
他们甚至都不会拉手
They wouldn't even be holding hands.
我也不肯定啊  毕竟你和他有过一腿
I wouldn't be so sure, he did it with you.
对啊  里克很信任我
Yeah, 'cause Bleek trusts me.
我们是好朋友
We're best friends.
你吃醋了?
Are you jealous?
我以为你不会在意他的事
I thought you said you didn't care what he did.
不是吃醋  不是在乎
Not jealous, don't care.
我只是不相信他会喜欢卡特里娜
I know Bleek doesn't like Katrina and he shouldn't
玩弄别人的感情  况且她真的很不错
toy with her emotions like that. She seems pretty nice.
啊哈  我确实相信
Uh- huh, I'm really convinced.
舞会是怪人才去的
Prom is for wenises, anyway.
长大后你会觉得一点也不好玩
As soon as you're old enough to go, it's so not cool anymore.
你真的要和卡特里娜・德・沃特一起去舞会?
Are you honestly and truly going to the prom with Katrina De Voort?
嗨!
Uh, hi?
只要跟我说"是"或"不是"?
Leah just said that you were gonna go with her.
对  我有问过她是否愿意去
Yeah, I did ask her if she wanted to go.
队里的人一起去本哈拿餐馆
A bunch of us from the team are going to Benihana,
然后去舞会  最后去维惴家的海边小屋
then go the prom, then go to Vijay's parents' cabin.
我们租了辆加长豪华车
We're getting a stretch limo.
你妈妈一定很高兴  你不是带我去
Your mom must be pretty stoked that you're not taking me.
你生气了  为什么?
You're mad. Why are you mad?
我没有生气
I'm not mad. I'm in a great mood.
我很平静  只是不满脱不了这肥厚衣服
Despite the fact that I'm in a fat suit I can't take off,
还有那些在我背后对我指指点点的人
despite the fact that pretty much everyone is making fun of me behind my back,
再有就是你那女朋友在课堂上瞪我看
despite the fact that your girlfriend gave me the stinkeye in art class yesterday.
卡特里娜不是我女朋友  我怀疑她有给你脸色看
Katrina's not my girlfriend! And I doubt that she gave you the stinkeye.
她脸长得就是那样  脸就那个样
That's just the way her face looks.
随你怎么说吧  你喜爱就跟那肉汤去吧
Just take Soupy Sales to prom,
我可以做些比那天晚上更酷的事情
I can think of so many cooler things to do that night.
我可以去磨磨我的脚  或去布伦那个笨教堂
I might pumice my feet or go to Bren's Unitarian church,
或者被一辆装着10吨果汁的卡车撞倒
maybe get hit by a truck full of hot garbage juice.
也总好过跟你去舞会
All those things would be exponentially cooler than going to the prom with you.
你的表现很不成熟
You're being really immature.
你没理由冲我发火  我是说
You have no reason to be mad at me. You broke my heart.
伤了我的心  我应该很生气
I should be royally ticked off at you.
应该很沮丧  或者不在理睬你
I should be really cheesed off. I shouldn't want to talk to you anymore.
就因为无聊和你上了床  然后也没打算和你结婚?
Why? Because I got bored and had sex with you, and then I didn't wanna, like, marry you?
如果和你结婚  恐怕你会是个泼妇
Like I'd marry you! You'd be the meanest wife ever.
而且我知道你那晚并不无聊
And I know that you weren't bored that day
因为那晚有很多电视节目
because there was a lot of stuff on TV.
而且《女巫布莱尔》也快开始了
The Blair Witch Project was coming on Starz, and you were like,
你说你没看过这个  我们应该看一下
"I haven't seen this since it came out,
但我们应该做点其他的事  叭啦叭啦
but we should make out instead. La la la. "
我想你该和那肉汤去舞会
You just take Katrina the Douche Packer to the prom.
免得以为我有多么的泼辣
I'm sure you two will have a real bitchin' time!
我还留着你的内裤呢
I still have your underwear.
我还留着你的童贞呢
I still have your virginity!
你可以闭嘴吗?
Would you shut up!
你感到羞耻了吗?
What? Are you ashamed that we did it?
-不是  -至少
- No. - 'Cause at least
你的衣服肚皮底下没有留下证据
you don't have to have the evidence under your sweater.
我可是怀孕了
I'm a planet!
等一下  让我帮你拿包
Wait, let me get your bag.
背多10磅又如何?
What's another ten pounds?
嗨!
Hi.
看来你很用功呢
Wow. That shirt's working hard.
瓦内萨在家吗?
Is Vanessa here?
不在  很安全
No. We are safe.
很高兴你能来  我有东西要给你
I'm glad you're here, I actually have something for you.
小心点
Almost there.
这里是婴儿房吗?  太妙了
Whoah, Mark! Is this the baby's room? It's beautiful!
你在开玩笑
Hilarious.
这里是我藏我的旧漫画书的地方
This is where I keep all my old comics,
给你看看这本
And I want to show you one.
你也这么喜欢漫画?
You're one of those guys?
看看
Take a look.
超丰满的Yuki
Most Fruitful Yuki?
那个怀孕女超人吗?
Is this a pregnant superhero?
不错吧!
Isn't that great?
我去日本时买的
I found it in Japan when I was there with my band.
让我想起了你
It reminds me of you.
我靠  当然了
Hells, yeah!
这的确让我感到自己和只母猪不一样了
This actually makes me feel way less of a fat dork.
Yuki爱惹是生非
Yuki is a real bad ass.
和你有共同点  你会感到很自豪
You should be very proud being in the same condition.
谢了
Thank you.
放点Toonish乐队音乐如何?
Oh, how about some tunage?
不要看CD目录  管它放那首
Alright, don't look, no matter what.
第一首有点慢
This one is actually kinda slow.
但这是他们的风格所以会很酷很硬
But it's Mott the Hoople so it's still totally rad and hardcore.
-怎么了?  -我听过这歌
I know this one.
-真的?  -对  它比我还年长
- You do? - Yeah, this song is older than I am.
我在高中舞会听过
I danced to this at my senior prom.
你舞伴是谁呢?
Who'd you dance with?
珊迪・安伯  一个很棒的舞伴
Cynthia Vogel, great dance partner.
她还让我把手放在她的胸上
She let me put my hands all over her butt.
很火辣
- Hot. - Very hot.
我可以想象你跳舞的样子
I can just, totally, picture you dancing,
像个傻瓜
Like a total dork!
事实上  也许  你的手应该  放在这儿
Her hands there,
我的手放这里
And my hands down here.
这就是我们88年的姿势
This is how we did it in '88.
像这样
Like this?
对
Just like this.
你以前跳过舞吗?
You've never been to a dance before?
只有呆子才会跳舞
Dances are for nerds and squares.
你呢?
What are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
感觉到我们中间隔着什么吗?
I feel like there's something between us.
我要离开瓦内萨了
I'm leaving Vanessa.
什么?
What?
我在城里找了个地方
I'm getting a place in the city.
我计划很久了  这是我长久以来一直想做的事
It's something I've wanted to do for a long time.
不可以
No!
不可以?
No?
你当然不可以这样做
No! You definitely can't do that.
这是件很重要的事
That's one big, fat sack of no!
不可以
有什么问题吗?
What is the matter?
我是说  你们必须照顾它啊  不是吗?
You guys are supposed to take care of this.
我想还行吧
I thought you'd be cool with this.
我想它能有个美满的家
I want things to be perfect.
而不是一个像其他支离破碎的家庭
I don't want them to be shitty and broken like everyone else's family.
听着  我一旦生下这个宝宝  瓦内萨会感到非常开心
Look, I'll have the baby, and Vanessa is going to be so happy.
宝宝不是我生活的一切
A baby is not going to fix everything.
我还未准备好做个父亲
Besides, I don't know if I'm even ready to be a father.
你已经很年长了
But you're old!
你对我是怎么想的?
How do you think of me?
为什么你要来这里?
Why are you over here?
我
I...
我只是想成为你另类生活的一部分
I just like being a piece of furniture in your weird life.
对  这就是我生活的状态
This is what my life has become. I got stuff in boxes.
被装在箱子里埋在地下  所以你感兴趣了?
I'm underground. That's appealing to you?
-这是我的错  -不是
- This is my fault. - No.
瓦内萨是因为我而对你不满吗?
Is Vanessa mad at you because of me?
与你无关  我和她已经没感觉了
That's got nothing to do with it. Vanessa and I aren't in love anymore.
如果你不爱她为何要结婚?
You were in love when you married her!
爱一个人是可以重新认识并相爱的
If you're in love once, you can be in love again.
像我好友莉亚和同一个人分分合合四次了
My friend Leah has been with the same guy four different times.
你只是不够努力
You're just not trying hard enough.
你应该责备我这种人
I'm such an idiot. I can't believe what an idiot I am.
不  知道吗  马克?
No, you know what, Mark.
不要抛弃你的妻子
Do not divorce your wife!
拜托了  当是做个好心  不要离开瓦内萨
Will you please just do me a solid and stay with Vanessa?
抱歉  我
You're so young.
我没那么小  我都16岁了
I'm not that young. I'm sixteen.
我已懂得分辨什么是混蛋了
I'm old enough to know when someone's acting like a total a- hole!
还有你知道吗?
Oh, and you know what,
我买了音速青年乐队的另一张专辑  烂掉渣了
I bought another Sonic Youth album and it sucks! It's just noise!
朱诺  怎么了?
Juno? What's going on?
没事
Nothing.
你为什么哭?
Why are you crying?
没有哭  我只是对豪华装修敏感
I'm not crying. I'm just allergic to fine home furnishings.
什么事?
What's the matter?
怎么了?
只是有点情绪波动
She's just a little hormonal. Right, Juno?
怀孕期间的反应
It's part of the process.
你干了什么?
What did you do?
没什么
I didn't do anything...
只不过
Just...
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
-什么?  -我一直在想这事是不是合适
- What? - Just thinking if this is the right thing.
你在胡说什么?
What are you talking about?
只是在怀疑是否
Just wondering if it's,
准备好了
Just wondering if we're ready.
我们准备好了
Yeah, we're ready.
我们准备好了  我们在上相关课程
We're ready. We've read the books, we've taken all the classes.
我们还有一个育婴室
We have a nursery that is completely...
听着  我知道事情安排好了  不过我怀疑自己还没准备好
Vanessa, I know we're prepared. I'm just wondering if... I'm ready.
先等等
Wait a minute.
朱诺  不要听他的  他只是有点沮丧
Juno, don't listen to him. He's just got cold feet.
他还是个小孩子
He's just being a guy.
书上也说了
The books all say the same thing.
当女人怀孕了就会成为妈妈
A woman becomes a mother when she gets pregnant.
当男人看到了宝宝出生他就会知道  要成为一个父亲了
A man becomes a father when he sees his baby.
他会明白的  他做得到的
He's going to get there.
这一切来得太快了
It just happened so fast.
我们登了广告  我以为会等好几个月
We put the ad in the paper and I thought it was gonna take months if at all and then,
然后两周后她就坐在我们沙发上了
Two weeks later, she's on that couch.
她是上天赐给我们的
She answered our prayers.
从那时候起  就像个定时的闹钟
Ever since then it's been like a ticking clock.
你说什么?
What are you saying?
我觉得是时辰未到
That it feels a little like bad timing.
那你眼中的好时辰是什么?  马克
What would be a good time for you, Mark?
等我做完我想做的事情
There's just some things that I still want to do.
例如什么?  做个摇滚巨星?
Like what? Be a rock star?
不要取笑我
Don't mock me.
我只能说这是
I'm just saying that this is,
这是永远不会发生的事情
This is something that's never going to happen.
知道吗  你的衬衫很稚气
Your shirt is stupid.
你是成年人了
Grow up.
假如要我等你成为科特・柯本(摇滚巨星)
If I have to wait for you to become Kurt Cobain,
我可能永远做不了妈妈
I'm never going to be a mother.
我从未说过我是个好爸爸
I never said I'd be a good father.
我打给吉托・拉斯了  她可以做两人的代表律师
I called Gerta Rauss and she said that she can represent both of us.
她称做是"合作性离婚"
It's called a "collaborative divorce. "
似乎现在很流行这样
It's all the rage right now, supposedly.
这应该很容易  因为我们没有孩子
And it would be pretty easy because we don't have any children.
谢谢你打给她了
Thanks for making the call, I guess.
你找到地方落脚了?
Have you found a place to stay yet?
-是的  在市中心  -酒店吗?
- Yeah, downtown. - A hotel?
不是酒店  是个公寓
No, it's not a hotel. It's a loft.
你还是个酷哥啊
Aren't you the cool guy?
我太想要个宝宝了
I wanted a baby so bad.
我明白
I know.
-好象是张帐单  -给我
- It looks like a bill from Jiffy- Lube. - It's for me.
我从未想过自己有这么想回到家
I never realize how much I like being home unless
除非是到另一个地方待上很久后
I've been somewhere really different for a while.
嘿  老爸
Hey, Dad.
嘿  加大码的朱朱
Hey, big puffy version of Junebug.
你去哪里了?
Where have you been?
我去了处理一些比较大人的事
Dealing with things way beyond my maturity level.
其他人呢?
Where is everybody?
布伦带小玛丽去上溜冰课了
Bren took Liberty Bell to her tot ice skating class.
你们不知道小孩子不能学滑冰吗?
When will you guys learn that tots can't ice skate?
宝贝  你有点不开心吗?
You're looking a little morose, honey.
什么事?
What's eating you?
好象我失去对人性的信心
I'm just, like, losing my faith with humanity.
你能清晰地告诉我吗?
Can you narrow that down for me?
我只是
I just...
怀疑
...wonder if...
两个人在一起生活是否合适
...two people can stay together for good.
你是说夫妻?
You mean like couples?
对  或是
Yeah, like,
相爱的两个人
People in love.
你遇到感情上的问题了?
Are you having boy trouble 'cause I gotta be honest;
因为我不确定你现在适合去约会
I don't really much approve of you dating in your condition,
那不是很好
That's kind of messed up.
不  不是这样爸爸
No, dad!
这有点猥亵感觉
I mean, that's pretty skanky.
像你们女孩子说的"猥亵"
Isn't that what you girls call it? Skanky? Skeevy?
不要说了
Please stop.
嗑药嗑疯了?
Tore up from the floor up?
不是这个啦
That's not what it's about.
我只是  想知道两个人  是否能开心地白头到老
I just need to know that it's possible that two people can stay happy together forever.
我敢说不容易就对了
It's not easy, that's for sure.
也许我不是个好的榜样  不过
I don't have the best track record in the world, I know, but,
我已经和你后妈生活10年了  我不敢说
I've been with your stepmother for ten years now,
我们生活得很美满愉快
and I'm proud to say that we're very happy.
听着
Look...
我是这样认为的
...In my opinion...
最好是找一个爱着你  就因为你是朱诺的人
The best thing you can do is find a person who loves you for exactly what you are.
开心  伤心  丑陋  美丽
Good mood, bad mood, ugly, pretty,
帅气  什么也好
Handsome, what have you,
总之对的那个人会觉得  你放的屁也是香的
the right person is still gonna think the sun shines out of your ass.
那个人才是我们  该与之厮守一生的
That's the kind of person that's worth sticking with.
没错
Yeah.
我想我已经遇到那个人了
I think I've found that person.
当然找到了  那就"D-A-D"  爸爸啊
Yeah, sure you have. Your old D- A- D!
我会永远爱你支持你
You know I'll always be there to love you, support you,
无论你闯了什么大祸
no matter what kind of pickle you're in.
绝对会
Obviously.
爸爸  我想要去
Dad, I think i'm just gonna,
去外面一会  不过
shove out for a sec, but,
应该很迟回来
I won't be home late.
好
Okay.
你说的那个人是我对吗?
You were talking about me, right?
对  没错
Oh, yeah.
里克  看看信箱
你好
Hi.
是你把100多盒  跳跳糖放进我信箱的吗?
Did you put like a hundred things of tic tacs in my mailbox?
对  那人是我
Oh, yeah, that was me.
为什么?
Why?
你知道  是你的最爱啊
They're your fave.
你永远都吃不厌那糖  所以我就
You can never have too many of your favorite one- calorie breath mint.
那谢谢你了
Yeah, well thanks, I...
我想那些糖够我吃到上大学了
I think I'm pretty much set until college on the tic tac front.
里克  知道吗?  我一直在想
You know, Bleek, I was thinking.
我不该那么凶对你  不是你的错
I'm sorry I was such a huge bitch to you. You don't deserve it.
没所谓  你知道
It's okay.
还有
Also,
我想我爱上你了
I think I'm in love with you.
你在开玩笑吗?
What, you mean as friends?
不
No.
我是说实话
I mean, for real.
因为你是我认识最酷的人
Because you're, like, the coolest person I've ever met.
而且你也没故意表现出来
And you don't even have to try.
其实我一直很努力表现
I try really hard, actually.
你单纯而聪明
You're, like, naturally smart.
你和其他人不一样
You're not like everyone else.
你一直看的是我的脸而不是肚子
You don't stare at my stomach all the time, you look at my face.
我看着你  宝宝就会踢我很厉害
And every time I see you, the baby starts kicking super hard.
真的?
It does?
我想是因为每次  我看你都心跳加快
I think it's because my heart starts pounding everytime I see you.
我也一样
Mine too.
这也是我从你那里得到的最大安慰了
That's all I could ask for.
黄金猛男
You're golden, man.
我们现在可以来吗?
Can we make out now?
可以
Yeah.
嘿  知道吗?  你们这样  脸贴脸可能会导致早产
You know, you can go into early labor sucking face like that!
爸爸!
Dad!
什么事?
What?
如果我不是尿床了  那就是
Dad, either I just peed my pants or...
那就是?
Or?
"雷猫跑车"要冲出来了
Thundercats are go!
快点快点
All out, all out!
你带了需要的东西了吗?
Do you have the admittance form?
没东西落下吧?
What about the parking stickers?
带好Liberty Bell
Have you got Liberty Bell?
忘记小玛丽了!
Oh, sweetie, sweetie!
我们走
Here we go.
快点  开车吧!
Hurry! Start the car, go!
爸爸
Gas!
-别这样  停下  -但这很有趣!
- Wait, wait! - Out of the way!
-不要这样  -为什么?
- Don't do that. - What?
-你们在疯什么?  -宝宝要出生了!
- That. - But it's fun!
怎么觉得是在做脊椎穿刺?
Bren, when do I get that friggin' Spinal Tap thing?
叫做脊髓阻滞  医生说你还不能生产
It's called a spinal block, and you can't have it yet, honey.
因为你还没有足够的张开度
The doctor said you're not dilated enough.
噢  去他的!  我感觉更难受了
Come on! I have to wait for it to get worse?
我只想快点处理完
Why can't I just have the friggin' thing now?
宝贝  医生就是虐待狂
Honey, doctors are sadists
就喜欢跟上帝对着干  就喜欢看小孩大喊大叫
who like to play God and watch lesser people scream.
噢  靠!
Oh, shit.
抱歉  能不能现在给孩子做脊椎穿刺?
Excuse me! Can we give my kid the damn spinal tap already?
然后
And then...
我不知道从哪里
out of nowhere...
出来了
...there it was...
他出生了
There he was.
我决定不告诉里克我要生了
I decided not to call Bleeker to tell him that I was having the baby.
他正要参加一项大比赛  我不想让他分心
He had a big meet against Manteno and I didn't want him to get all worried about me.
不过他还是感觉到了
But he figured it out anyway.
某天你会再回来的  宝贝
Someday you'll be back here, honey.
以你的名义
On your terms.
嗨
Hey.
谢谢你来了
Nice legs.
里克决定不去看宝宝
Bleeker decided he didn't want to see the baby.
我也是  我们觉得他不是属于我们的
Neither did I, really. He didn't feel like ours.
我想应该是属于她的
I think he was always hers.
你要看看你儿子吗?
Would you like to meet your son?
我有个儿子了
I have a son?
我看起来怎样?
How do I look?
一个真正的妈妈
Like a new mom.
担心又爱怜的妈妈
Scared shitless.
然后又以一张椅子结束了
It ended with a chair.
致瓦内萨:
如果你还坚持  那我也是一样--朱诺
夏天来了
保利・里克作为我的男友是我的一切
As boyfriends go, Paulie Bleeker is totally boss.
就像通心粉里面的芝士般重要
He is the cheese to my macaroni.
我知道人们一般是先恋爱再生育
I know people are supposed to fall in love before they reproduce, but,
我自知不是个循规蹈矩的人  那不是我的风格
I guess normalcy's not really our style.
嘿
Hey.
准备好了?
Ready?
是的
Yeah.
You're a part time lover and a full time friend
The monkey on you're back is the latest trend
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...
Here is the church and here is the steeple
We sure are cute for two ugly people
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...
We both have shiny happy fits of rage
You want more fans, I want more stage
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...
You are always trying to keep it real
I'm in love with how you feel
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...
I kiss you on the brain in the shadow of a train
I kiss you all starry eyed, my body's swinging from side to side
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...
The pebbles forgive me the trees forgive me
So why can't, you forgive me?
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...
Du du du du du du du du
I don't see what anyone can see
in anyone else...But you...